我们到目前为止一直在为派对制作客人名单
We've been making a guest list so far for the party.
—— 等等 这个是为生日派对准备的客人名单 是吗 凯瑟琳？
&gt;&gt; Wait, this is the guest list for the birthday party, right, Catherine?
—— 是啊
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
—— 我希望我也能在名单上
&gt;&gt; I really hope I'm on this list.
—— 好吧 让我们研究一下
&gt;&gt; Well, we'll have to see about that.
—— 哇哦 我觉得那真的很害羞(feel small)
&gt;&gt; Wow, I feel really small about that.
—— 那么 说到小(small)
&gt;&gt; Well, speaking about small,
我们讨论一下屏幕上View的尺寸大小
let's talk about the size of views on a screen.
—— 哦 我们已经用了既定的高度 用dp表示的 不是吗？
&gt;&gt; Oh, we've used the fixed written height, which is the dp, right?
—— 是的 高度和宽度都是
&gt;&gt; Yeah, the width and height.
而且我们也可以设定View紧密包含内容(wrap_context)
And we could also set, wrap content, with view.
—— 没错 View把自己围绕着内容包紧
&gt;&gt; Right, which is a strange way of saying that the view is going to
实在是一种奇怪的说法
wrap itself around the content.
应该是当内容变大
So the content grows large,
View也会变大 内容变小 View也会变小
the view grows large, the content is small and the view grows small.
—— 是的 然而还有第三种 叫做“匹配父元素”(match_parent)
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and there's actually a third one which is called, match parent.
—— 听起来很奇怪
&gt;&gt; That seems a little strange.
听起来像单身父母的约会网站
That sounds like a dating website for single parents.
—— 并不
&gt;&gt; Not quite.
和父元素匹配是说View的高或宽会和父元素一样
Match parent means that the view will be As wide or as tall as the parent.
—— 哦 这样就说得通了
&gt;&gt; Oh, so that makes sense.
我是一个View 我有一个父元素而且
I am a view, I have a parent and my width and
我的高度和我的宽度将会和父元素保持一致
height is going to be the same as my parent.
好 —— 准确地说
Okay. &gt;&gt; Exactly, so that's to summarize,
为了改变View的尺寸 你可以为宽度设定不同值
the different values that you can set for a size of a view is width.
高度和宽度可以用dp指定
Fixed dp for width and height.
—— 没错 你也可以设定wrap_content
&gt;&gt; Correct, you can also do wrap_content.
接下来我们将要尝试的是
And the next one we're going to try out is
—— match_parent
&gt;&gt; match_parent.
这里是几个线性布局中设定不同宽度
Here are some examples of how setting different widths on the child views
最终影响到用户界面的例子
in a linear layout can affect the final user interface.
这个例子中我们把每个子元素的View宽度设定为200dp
In this example we set each child view to have a fixed width of 200 dp.
如果每个View里的内容大于200dp
If the content inside each view is greater than 200 DP
你就会冒有部分内容被截断的风险
then you run risk of cutting some content off like this.
这个例子中我们设置每个子元素的View宽度为wrap_content
In this example we set each child view to have a width a wrap content.
现在所有的内容都被显示出来了
Now all the content content is shown, but
但是每个View的宽度随着内容的不一致而不一致
the width of each view really varies based on what's inside each view.
这个例子中 我们设置每个子元素的View为match_parent
In this example, we set the width of each child view to be match parent.
现在你可以看见每个子元素的宽度和父元素的一样
Now you see that the width of each child is as wide as the parent view group.
无关其内容
Regardless of the content inside of it.
现在这些值也可以被应用于每个View的高度
Now those same values can also be applied for the height of each view.
这个例子中我们把每个子元素的高度设置为200dp
In this example we set the height of this child text view to be 200 dp.
如果内容本身高度大于200dp
If the content inside it is taller than that.
你就有可能截断部分内容
Then you run the risk of cutting off some of the content.
在这个例子中 我们设置每个子元素为wrap_content
In this example, we set the height of the child text view to be wrap content.
这样 所有内容就会被显示在屏幕上
That way all the content will be displayed on screen and
而且没有截断 因为TextView的高度决定于其
nothing will be cut off because the size of the text view is dependent
里面的内容
on the content inside of it.
这个例子中 我们设置每个子元素的高度为match_parent
In this example, we set the height of the child text view to be match parent.
这样子View就会和父元素一样高
That way the child view is as tall as the parent itself,
而无视其内部内容
regardless of the content inside it.
我们现在打开XML可视化器
Let's open the XML visualizer now and
试着在代码里面做这些
try to be more like our parents in the code.
我们在下面的教师笔记中提供了XML可视化器的链接
We're providing you a link to the XML visualizer with some starter code
还有一些初始代码
in the instructor notes below.
在本例中 线性布局是根View
In this case, the LinearLayout is the root view
因为他是第一个和最外面的View
of this layout because it's the first and outermost view.
如果我们为根View的高度和宽度设置match_parent
If we set match_parent for the width and height of this root view, and
并把这种布局设置为主要布局
we set this as the main layout of our app,
那么这个线性布局就会和设备的高和宽一致
then this linear layout will be as tall and wide as the device screen.
我可以通过设置这个线性布局的背景为非透明
I can show you by setting the background of this linear layout
让你看得更清楚
to be a non-transparent color.
如果我设置了一个灰色的背景
If I set a gray background color on this linear layout Then,
你就会看到灰色占据了整个设备的高和宽
you can see how the gray extends the full width and height of the device.
现在 如果我改变这些TextView的宽度和高度为match_parent
Now, what happens if I try to change the width or
将会发生什么？
height of these text views to be match parent?
为了搞清楚每个View的边界
To make it clear where the bounds of each view are,
我将为每一个View设置背景颜色
I'm going to set a background color on each of the views.
现在我把这个TextView设置为match_parent
Now I'm going to change the height of this text view to be match parent.
顺便说一句 它的拼写是match_parent
By the way, you spell it match_parent.
现在你可以看到这个TextView占据了父元素的全部高度
And now you see that this text view takes up the full height of the parent.
不幸的是 它把所有其他的东西都推到了屏幕外面
Unfortunately, it pushes everything else off the screen, so
我们不希望看到这些
we don't really want that.
那么我们就把它换回wrap_content
So let's change it back to wrap content.
好
Okay.
我们把宽度改成match_parent 看看会有什么变化
So let's change the width now to be match parent and see what it does.
现在TextView的宽度就和父元素一样了 也就是说
Now the width of the TextView is as wide as the parent, which in turn,
和设备屏幕的宽度一样
is as wide as the device screen.
如果我把其他TextView也换成match_parent
If I change the other TextViews to also be match_parent
你可以看见它也开始占据了父元素的全部宽度
You can see that it also starts to take up the full width of the parent.
我也想指出另外一件事
I also want to point out one more thing.
每当你看见以"layout_"开头的属性名称
Every time you see an attribute that starts with layout underscore, like
如layout_height或layout_width 这些是视图组(view group)的布局信息
layout height or layout width, these are actually view group layout parameters.
他们也被父视图组(view group)使用以确定
These are used by the parent view group to determine the size and
View的尺寸和位置
the position of these views.
同时 其他属性 诸如背景 文字大小
Meanwhile, the other attributes like background, text size, and
和文字由TextView本身处理以自定义它的风格
text are handled by the TextView in terms of styling its own view.
但是这些视图组(view group)的布局参数由其父元素处理
But these view group layout parameters are handled by the parent.
现在 该由你来试试不同的宽度和高度值了
Now it's your turn to try different width and height values.
下面的教师笔记
For the link to the XML visualizer with some starter code,
有配备初始代码的XML可视化器
see the instructor notes below.
试着去改变每个TextView的宽度和高度
Try to change the width and height values of each TextView.
你可以设置一个既定的dp值 或warp_content match_parent
You can set a fixed dp value, wrap-content, or match_parent.
记住 每个View的宽度和高度不一定要一致
Remember that for each view, the width and height values don't have to match.
当你完成之时 点选这个方框以继续
When you're done, check this box to continue.